RAYMOND CAMDEN

Lafayette, Louisiana | (337) 412-8987 | raymondcamden@gmail.com | www.raymondcamden.com

DEVELOPER ADVOCACY AND EVANGELISM

Experienced developer evangelist with a proven track record of building relationships with developers and helping them succeed. I'm a trusted voice in technical communities with a history of delivering engaging presentations and creating easy to understand blog posts and documentation. I've published multiple books, written over six thousand blog posts, and have spoken to audiences around the globe.

EXPERIENCE

Adobe, Principal Developer Evangelist

2021-2024

- Developer Evangelism: Created new documentation and revamped existing resources to help our developers onboard to our APIs and services, directly leading to a 33% increase in developer sign ups. Launched an Office Hours program for Acrobat Services APIs to connect developers with evangelists.
- Thought Leadership: Introduced developers to our APIs via blog posts (60+), presentations and workshops (30+). Created demo content to inspire and educate developers on the capabilities of our offerings.
- Developer Advocacy: Worked with engineering to provide feedback from our developers and help guide new releases to be more successful and developer-friendly. Helped create new processes for the publication of new releases and updates.
- Team Collaboration: Mentored fellow evangelists and helped my team deliver projects that directly helped both our developers and sales teams better demonstrate our APIs.

HERE Technologies, Lead Developer Evangelist

2019-2021

- Developer Evangelism: Created multiple blog posts (30+), presentations (20+), and demonstrations for the HERE Platform.
- Developer Advocacy: Used my experience with our developers to provide feedback to engineering to help evolve our offerings.
- Competitive Analysis: Conducted research into competitors' products and services to identify gaps in our offering and opportunities for growth. Created documentation for our developers to more easily migrate to HERE.
- Team Collaboration: Helped mentor new developer evangelists on the team. Provided suggestions, feedback, and advice to help them be more successful.

American Express, Senior Engineer, Developer Experience 2018-2019

 Developer Evangelism: Worked with engineering and product management to define onboarding and user-education processes for

- new APIs and offerings.
- Developer Advocacy: Reviewed existing offerings and worked on documentation improvements to help new developers.
- Engineering: Worked on both code and documentation (in both Java and Node.js) for existing APIs to make them easier to use.

Auth0, Senior Developer Advocate

2018-2018

- Developer Evangelism: Helped promote a new offering, Auth0 Extend, by creating documentation, demos, and blog posts, introducing the offering to existing and new Auth0 developers.
- Team Collaboration: As a team member working on a new product, I helped with product direction and development.

IBM, Developer Advocate

2015-2018

- Developer Evangelism: Helped evangelize both IBM products and open source offerings, including LoopBack, Node.js, and the serverless platform, OpenWhisk. Wrote the book on OpenWhisk and helped developers use serverless technologies.
- Thought Leadership: Presented at conferences around the world, both on our offerings as well as open source solutions.
- Team Leadership: Helped expand our team with interviewing and mentoring new hires.

Adobe, Senior Developer Evangelist, Developer

2011-2015

- Developer Evangelism: Helped promote new offerings to the web platform, including HTML5 tools as well as mobile development technologies.
- Thought Leadership: Helped introduce developers to new capabilities of the web platform and embrace standards-based mobile development with the open source Apache Cordova project.
- Team Collaboration: Helped with Creative Cloud Learn team with documentation and back-end development.
- Community Engagement: Helped build and manage the tool used by hundreds of Adobe User Groups world-wide.

EDUCATION

University of Louisiana at Lafayette, English with a Minor in Computer Science. Bachelor's Degree in 1995.

SKILLS

Developer evangelism and advocacy, technical writing and editing, API development and usage, generative AI, JavaScript and the Web Platform, Node.js, Python, public speaking.